Before I do task 29,
I'm going to show you an
example of the function "foldr".
As you can see, we have a function f here.
And we're defining something called a.
And a is equal to foldr
with this function, and
the c as 0, and this list.
And this a evaluates to the following.
So, what you're doing here is:
f of two things... two parameters.
This is the x, and this is the y.
And the y itself is f of 2 and this.
And this is also f of 1 and 0.
So, what is f of 1 and 0?
It is 1.
And then you get this.
You continue… you do the same
and you get 11 in the end.
So, at the beginning, when dealing with the
function foldr, it's nice to do some evaluation
to practice using it, by doing some
examples like this and trying to calculate…
trying to guess what the result would be.
...
This is my guess.
Now let's see if this is true.
So, now I just write a and, yes, we get 11.
Okay, so now let's do the task. We have this.
This is the original function.
We need to write it with foldr.
Let's say, for example, we have this list and
we want to evaluate “original” of this list.
So, we want to evaluate the application
of this function on this list.
The first number in this list is 11.
And it fulfills this condition.
So, we get 13 + the “original”
of the “tail” of the list.
Then we do the same.
We have 22. And 22 also fulfills the condition.
So, we get another 13 + “original”
of the “tail” of the list.
Now we have 1, so it doesn't
fulfill this condition.
So, we get x multiplied by
“original” of the “tail” of the list.
And our x, in this case, is 1. So, we get
1 multiplied by “original” of this list.
We continue. We do the same. So, now we have 2.
It stays as it is, and we multiply by
“original” of the list which contains only 33.
But this time, 33 fulfills the condition, so we
get 13 + “original” of the “tail” of the list,
which is the empty list. And now we are at
this case: the “origin” of the empty list is 7.
Now we have just numbers. So, 13 + 7
is 20. 20 multiplied by 2 and so on…
until we reach the final result which
is 66. Let's test this. Yes, it is 66.
Okay, now let's make a function
f. And it takes x and y.
x is going to be this x and y is going to be
“original” applied to the “tail” of the list.
So, we say: if x fulfills this
condition, then we just do 13,
and we add it to, as you can see, y, which
is “original” of the “tail” of the list.
So, we have 13 + “original”
of the “tail” of the list.
If it doesn't fulfill the
condition, then we have x as it is,
multiplied by “original”
of the “tail” of the list,
which is this case here.
1 is x, and “original” of
the “tail” of the list is y.
Now let's write the function “alternative”.
So, “alternative” takes a list of
integers and gives a single integer.
Foldr… And we use this function here,
and we give it a starting value which is 7.
And then we write the list. But as you
can see, we have “list” here and here,
and it is the last argument on the right side.
So, we can just do eta reduction.
And this means we don't
need to write this at all.
Now I'm going to do the
function f as a lambda function.
And that's it. Now let me test the solution.
Main. And as you can see, it is working.
Now, just to make sure,
I'm going to do evaluation.
And I copy the definition of the
function “foldr” from the lecture slides.
I'm going to use the same list here.
But this time, we're doing it with “alternative”.
So, we say: “alternative” of this list.
And we're going to follow
the definition step by step.
So, is the list empty? No, it's not empty.
So, we go to this case here.
And we get f x, which is the
first number, which is 11.
And then, in brackets, we have foldr
f and the initial value which is c,
which is 7, and the “tail”
of the list [22, 1, 2, 33].
What is foldr f 7 and the tail of the list?
Again, the list is not empty,
so we go to this case,
and we get f and the first element, which is 22.
And in brackets, we have foldr f 7
the tail of the list [1, 2, 33].
Again f 11... f 22 foldr. No... so, foldr
of this is going to be the first element.
I mean f then x, which is the first element, and
then, again in brackets, we're going to have foldr
f 7 the tail of the list
and f 2... foldr f 7 and the list
containing 33. I'm just going to copy this.
Then here we're going to have
f 33.
And then, in brackets, we're going
to have foldr f 7 the empty list.
Now we know what foldr does with an empty list.
It just gives us c.
And c, in our case, is 7.
So, here we have 7.
Now, what is f of 33 and 7?
So, let's look here.
Is 33 mod 11 equal to 0?
Yes. This means we get 13 + y,
which is the second argument,
which is, in our case, this 7. So, this
means here we get 13 + 7, which is 20.
So, now what is f of 2 and 20?
Is 2 mod 11 equal to 0?
No.
So, we get x multiplied by y, which means 40.
Now, again, what is f of 1 and 40?
1 mod 11 is not equal to 0.
So, this means we get x multiplied by y.
We get 40 multiplied by 1, which is 40.
f of 22 and 40 is 13 + 40.
So, it is 53.
Now, what is f of 11 and 53? So, 11 mod 11 is 0.
This means we get 13 + 53.
And now we have 66, which is the
same result that we got here.
And that's it.